

Projects

A list of software systems I have developed

∠ink

Languages

Norwegian

Mother tongue

English

Fluent, professionally

French

Turkish

Second language

Personal skills

Teamwork- and solution-oriented. Social, dedicated and passionate. Creative problem-solver. Cool-headed under pressure.

Technical skills

Full-stack AWS cloud development

Debian Linux (Bash-shell - Systemd)

Python (AWS Lambda - Flask - Django)

JavaScript (node.js - ReactJS - AngularJS)

SQL (PostgreSQL - PostGIS - SQL-Server)

PHP (Composer - Laravel)

Web servers (NGINX - Apache)

Microsoft Dynamics 365 (with SSRS and

Personal interests Sailing, Fitness training, Mountain

SSIS)

Java

hiking, Snorkeling and freediving, Classical art and history

Andreas Atakan

Full-stack developer specialised in geospatial applications

Ø Bergen, Norway **\(+4748006325** andreascan.98@gmail.com Attps://andreasatakan.com/ December 5, 1998 (Bergen, Norway)

Profiles

in <u>LinkedIn</u>

GitHub

Summary

I am a full-stack developer specialised in geospatial data with mapapplications. I have a unique skill set that combines all facades of webtechnologies (full-stack; all stages of software development) and AWS cloud infrastructure with geospatial analysis and visualisation.

University of Bergen

Education

Computer science

Bachelor's degree

August 2017 - December 2020

Description Bachelor's degree in computer science at the University of Bergen

Department of Informatics was a three year program that gave me extensive experience in all areas of software development and systems architecture. It gave me a solid foundation for the experience I would gain later in my working career.

Co-founder

Experience

https://nfedb.no/

Nordfjord EDB AS

Bergen, Norway

January 2022 - Present

Since January 2022 I worked at the consulting firm Nordfjord EDB AS with a co-founder. We do a number of consulting projects for customers in the

forest industry and nature conservation industry where we have done extensive GIS analyses as part of the projects. We have also done a number of projects in the public sector where we have developed areaaccounts of building-plans and their impacts for municipalities and counties. We have also analysed area-accounts at the property-level for the private sector. We started the innovation project GeoTales, a mapbased story-telling tool, and have received funding by Innovation Norway at commercialisation-level. Napkin AS September 2019 – January 2022

https://napkin.no/

I founded Napkin AS together with two other co-founders. We worked on

March 2020 – January 2022

Stavanger, Norway

the innovation project NapkinGIS, which aimed to create a used-friendly

Co-founder and CTO

and more accessible web-based GIS analysis and visualisation tool. The NapkinGIS project was funded by Innovation Norway, both at the marketdiscovery and commercialisation level. I was responsible for all technical development in the project. The project saw initial commercial success with multiple paying customers. Two of the founders went on to start the consulting firm Nordfjord EDB AS. GitHub page showcasing the entire code-base and subsystems.

Senior consultant Stavanger, Norway

https://friendos.com/ I worked as a hired senior consultant and developer on the innovation

Friend Software Corporation AS

were the development of the systems map-module which could handle advanced visualisations of geospatial data. The project received funding from Innovation Norway at the highest levels, and has seen international commercial success. The <u>GitHub page</u> of the project where I made code contributions Cartagena AS December 2017 – September 2019

project FriendOS which aimed to create a fully self managed web-based operating system not reliant on big cloud providers. My responsibilities

https://www.cartagena.no/ From December 2017 to September 2019 I worked as a junior developer

Junior developer

at Cartagena AS. I worked on maintaining the Microsoft Dynamics CRM system for some of the companies biggest customers. This included working on new and existing SQL-Server entities in the system, and

Bergen, Norway

integrating these entities with the reporting- and accounting-systems. Our customers used Visma as their accounting system, so I also gained some limited experience with that. EPOS, the European Plate Observing March 2016 – December 2016 **System** Bergen, Norway Technical intern

a complete website for the Norwegian sub-sector of the European Plate Observatory System (EPOS-Norway).

https://epos-no.uib.no/#/

In this project I was able to exercise my experience in full-stack webdevelopment using PHP and PostgreSQL. This website included user registration and an events-system where a registered user could create, update and delete and events from a calendar. The user- and events-

From March to December in 2016 I designed, developed and maintained

system was entirely written by myself. References **Trond Simensen** Senior researcher at the Norwegian Institute for Nature Research (NINA)

Hogne Titlestad Founder and former CEO at Friend Software Corporation AS

Knut-Eivind Handeland Chairman and Former manager, Cartagena AS

+47 906 97 989, keh@cartagena.no **Øyvind Natvik**

+47 407 29 656 , ht@friendup.cloud

+47 415 09 167, trond.simensen@nina.no

Chief Engineer, Department of Earth Science, University of Bergen

+47 55 58 27 96, Oyvind.Natvik@uib.no Reference from my work with EPOS-Norway

Awards

Validé NapkinGIS was named the winner of Validé's ITSA start-up awards as the

ITSA Start

best project in their program, and received a prize of NOK 300,000 and a seat at their incubator.

June 2020

Publications Planlagt utbyggingsareal i Norge. Identifisering av mulig August 2023

framtidig utbyggingsareal ... Norwegian Institute for Nature Research (NINA)

https://brage.nina.no/nina-xmlui/handle/11250/3085779 Under the auspices of Nordfjord EDB AS, I co-authored a research-article

published by the Norwegian Institute for Nature Research (NINA), where

we identified all possible panned development areas in Norway and their environmental impact in terms of the nature resources already present in those areas. I was, together with a co-author from NINA, responsible for the underlying GIS analysis that identified the development areas and their overlap with existing nature resources.

After finishing the article we created a map visualisation of the results, that can be found <u>here</u>.